ARI KAMLANI

DATA SCIENTIST | TECHNOLOGIST <u>linkedin.com/in/akamlani</u> ♦ <u>arikamlani.com</u> +1 (415) 926-1221 ♦ <u>akamlani@gmail.com</u> San Francisco, CA. USA

SUMMARY

Data Scientist and former Technologist with 15+ years of overall experience, including a history of delivering strategic large-scale projects in fast-paced environments. Experienced across the entire lifecycle, from ideation and prototyping through product development and certification. Particularly focused on initiatives for alleviating user and technology pain points for further advancements. Prior background includes experience with IoT, Wireless Technology, Embedded Software, and OEM Reference Semiconductor designs.

EDUCATION

Galvanize – San Francisco, CA – *Data Science Immersive Bootcamp (Jun 2016-Aug 2016)*Data ScienceTech Institute (DSTI) – Paris, France - *Part-Time Data Scientist Designer (Oct 2015-May 2016)*General Assembly – San Francisco, CA – *Part-Time Data Science (Oct 2014 – Dec 2014)*Lehigh University – Bethlehem, PA - *Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering (1999)*

Select Recent Trainings (Paris, France):

Distributed Computing with Apache Spark (1.6.1) – Scala Focused IBM Analytics Ecosystem SAS Enterprise Miner, Visual Analytics *MOOC Certifications:*

Scalable Machine Learning (Apache Spark - PySpark): (edX, 2015)

Enabling Technologies for Data Science and Analytics - The Internet of Things: (edX, 2016)

Independent Coursework/Workshops:

Big Data, Data Science, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Sabermetrics Creativity & Innovation, Idea Incubation, Design Thinking

EXPERIENCE

Inria Research Institute ♦ Sophia Antipolis, France ♦ Jan 2016 – Mar 2016

Part-Time Research — STARS (Spatio-Temporal Activity Recognition Systems) Research Team Computer vision Semantic Scene interpretation per preventive care and diagnosis for the elderly.

- Enhanced event recognition models of manually identified zones in the home
- Improved upon the structure interpretation of missing ground truth scenarios

Nagra Kudelski Group ♦ San Francisco, CA ♦ 2012-2015

Software Expert - Group Innovation

Technologist within R&D Innovation Group responsible for future Technology and Application Advancement.

- Initiated new project proposals and presentations to present to executive board.
- Ideation in relation to Intellectual Property (IP), creation of Patents, and formation of new business units.
- Formulated new strategic Partner Vendor relationships to strengthen selected projects.
- Executed multiple future generation technology research and assessment special project directives.
- Led Proof of Concept (POC) designs centered on Long-Range People Tracking. Design was focused on achieving the Active RFID range benefits with a Battery-Assisted Passive (BAP) RFID design at a fraction of the cost.

SPORTVISION ♦ Mountain View, CA ♦ 2011-2012

Embedded Software Consultant - Motorsports Division

Special Projects Consultant reporting to office of CTO for Motorsports (NASCAR Trucks) division, advising in the development of vehicle tracking, local base station communication, and sensor measurement.

- Successfully delivered custom in-house Embedded Linux Kernel (2.6.35) and root filesystem distribution.
- Enhanced communication signaling between OMAP (OMAP3530) and AVR (Atmel).
- Decreased system boot time and improved system stability issues.
- Custom feature design to allow for remote update images in the field.

Broadcom → Sunnyvale, CA → 2011

Principal Engineer – Systems Engineering, Cellular Division

Responsible for WiMAX and LTE radio network driver systems software architecture mobile reference designs.

- Directed platform requirements, architecture, and integration of vendor Voice over LTE (VoLTE).
- Managed customer (RIM) migration platform architecture (OMAP 3530, 4430) from Linux to QNX.
- Led multi-site customer and group project management task coordination.
- Guided technology teams per next generation mobile platform processor architecture and requirements.

Qualcomm → Raleigh, NC → 2007-2010

Staff Engineer – Computing and Consumer Division

Responsible for Windows Mobile board support package (BSP) Snapdragon ARM Cortex based reference designs.

- Engaged in cross-disciplinary technical reviews with multi-site technology teams to access processor requirements, identify next generation features, and improve upon the current reference design.
- Enhanced systems performance initiatives, to further optimize boot time, perform monitors and latency.
- Advised OEMs in custom feature development and in successfully achieving certification requirements.

Additional Experiences:

TapRoot Systems: Morrisville, NC: 2003-2007, Principal Engineer/Technical Lead – Mobile Products and Services Panasonic Mobile Communications, Suwanee, GA: 2000-2003, Senior Software Engineer – Mobile Platforms Verizon Wireless, Plymouth Meeting, PA: 1999-2000, RF Systems Performance Engineer – Systems Performance

Technical Skills

Data Analysis Jupyter (IPython Notebook), Yhat Rodeo, R Studio, Zeppelin

Distributed Systems Apache Spark (1.6.1)

SAS SAS Enterprise Miner, SAS Visual Analytics
IBM BigInsights, SPSS Modeler, Bluemix, Watson

Databases SQLite, PostreSQL, MySQL

Programming Python, R, Scala, SQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS, C, C++, ARM Assembler, VHDL

OOD Modeling UML, OCL

Frameworks Bootstrap, Foundation, Jekyll Project Management Agile Scrum (Pivotal Tracker)

SCM/Tracking Git, Perforce, ClearCase, ClearQuest, SVN, PVCS, Bugzilla

Requirements Management Doors

Operating Systems Linux/Unix, QNX Nucleus Plus, Windows Mobile/WinCE, Symbian

IDE Eclipse, IntelliJ, Spyder, GDB, Trace32 Lauterbauch, QNX Momentics IDE,

MSFT Visual Studio, Platform Builder, ARM Development Suite, Rational Rose RT,

CodeWarrior

Patents

- Interference Control in Wireless Communication; United States 13/887,039 (Filed: 05/03/2013)
- Device Localization Based on a Learning Model; United States 14/311,077 (Filed: 06/20/2014)